CHERYL CARPENTER

WEB DEVELOPER

I am a versatile, frontend web developer with a strong background in graphic design. I develop responsive, feature-rich, customer-facing websites using latest web technologies. I design easy-to-use and maintain content-managed experiences for enterprise marketing departments. I can work from the conceptual stage to the digital product launch.

TECHNOLOGY STACKS

CODING:

HTML5, css/sass/scss, jQuery, JavaScript, PHP, C#/MVC, gulp, webpack

THIRD-PARTY

Github, Bitbucket, Jira, git, TFS, Google Analytics, SalesForce API, Crazy Egg, Silverpop, Akamai, AWS, Visual Studio, VS Code, Atom

FRAMEWORKS

Bootstrap, Foundataion, Bulma

SERVER

Linux, Crontab, MySQL, phpMyAdmin, cPanel

CMS

WORDPRESS: installation, migration & maintenance, security, custom theme development, custom plugin development, SEO, BuddyPress, bbPress, Yoast

 $\mathit{UMBRACO}$ (ASP.NET): installation, migration & maintenance, customization, custom modules, SEO

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER @ LANVERA

10/2019-CURRENT | Coppell, Texas

(06/2020 - current)

Frontend developer - MVC/C#

Using the design library I created for in-house, I am now helping implement the frontend into MVC applications. I am working on every piece of the application up-to and except the database. I use my design background to translate the design-vision and business requirements into usable code.

(10/2019 - 06/20120)

Frontend developer - static HTML prototypes

I created a pixel-perfect design library from UI mockups, delivering fully functional javascript, HTML, and SCSS for several SASS applications. I created a Node.js stack to implement static data and a feature-rich frontend.

WEB DEVELOPER @ FIRST-AMERICAN PAYMENT SYSTEMS 2016-10/2019 | Fort Worth, Texas

Developed all front-end and administrative functionalities for content managed, marketing websites. Adhered to all best practices for code, mobile devices and SEO. Integrated lead-generating forms with SalesForce API. Provided ongoing support.

WORDPRESS DEVELOPER @ AT&T

2015-2016 | Dallas, Texas

Supported WordPress community with development and business process oversight. Designed and launched original marketing initiatives including contests and lead-generating efforts. Oversaw the migration of the project from an outside agency to internal servers.

- Selected and led two co-developers
- Wrote custom WordPress plugins around marketing initiatives
- Converted large set of LESS stylesheets to SASS for forward compatibility with Bootstrap

WEB DESIGNER / DEVELOPER @ FIRST WEB MARKETING

2013-2015 | Fort Worth, Texas

Designed original WordPress themes and plugins for local, service-oriented businesses.

- Introduced the team to css preprocessors
- Wrote processes and best practices for css stylesheets
- Used Schema code for local SEO results

WEB DESIGNER / DEVELOPER @ SHEPLERS INC, ECOMMERCE 2012-2013 | Frisco, Texas

Designed, coded and launched retail-to-consumer emails and ecommerce landing pages. Developed HTML emails and uploaded to Silverpop Engage. Tested emails using Litmus. Updated webpages and performed site maintenance using html, css, and OCP site manager by Fry Micros. Created brand-consistent marketing campaigns for website and social media use using Adobe Creative Suite.

- Led initiative to bring the html coding of our email files in-house.
- Scripted email link replacements from excel to html code using python
- Cross-browser/client compatibility testing using Litmus

DIGITAL MEDIA DESIGNER @ INSPIRUS

2009-2012 | Fort Worth, Texas

Created interactive training products for proprietary software customers (SaaS). Scripted Adobe Flash (ActionScript) to create personalized customer login portals for digital product (SaaS). Worked with team of creatives to create

formal Request for Proposals. Learned new products, techniques, applications, and systems as needed.

EDUCATION

 ${\bf BA\ JOURNALISM\ -\ University\ of\ North\ Texas} \\ {\bf CONTINUING\ EDUCATION\ -\ @FreeCodeCamp}$

CHANNELS

twitter: @thedesignsprite

email: cherylcarpenter 2015 'at' gmail 'dot' com github: https://github.com/cherylcarpenter

HOBBIES

I'm a huge booknerd, of mostly stuff and nonsense, follow me on Goodreads!